‫Ari4KD · גרסה 1 · ✓ מסונכרן לקובץ‬
‫החומות עמדו‬
‫איתן במשך מאה שנה.‬
‫מבצר של שלום וביטחון.‬
‫האימה לחיות תחת חסדיהם‬
‫נעלמה כלא הייתה.‬
‫האנושות התרגלה‬
‫לחיות כמו בקר.‬
‫ואז...‬
‫♪♪ מוזיקה עוצמתית מתנגנת...‬
‫♪♪‬
‫הטיטאנים פרצו את מה‬
‫שלקחנו כמובן מאליו‬
‫במשך זמן רב.‬
‫המאבק על הישרדות‬
‫האנושות החל.‬
‫המוות שלט בכול,‬
‫גובה קורבנות מחיילים‬
‫ומאזרחים כאחד.‬
‫מספר האבדות היה מזעזע.‬
‫מזעזעת לא פחות הייתה הידיעה‬
‫שנרכשה בדם יזע ודמעות,‬
‫שהטיטאנים מסתתרים‬
‫בינינו.‬
‫חמש שנים אחרי‬
‫נפילת החומה הראשונה,‬
‫הצלחנו ללכוד בחיים‬
‫אחד מהיצורים‬
‫הבוגדניים האלה.‬
‫חיילת עמיתה.‬
‫אני לאונהארט.‬
‫ובכל זאת,‬
‫גם כשהתפזר עשן‬
‫הקרב,‬
‫האיום הבא כבר‬
‫עמד בפתח.‬
‫מה לעזאזל...?‬
‫חבר'ה! תסתכלו!‬
‫מ-מה זה?‬
‫זה טיטאן!‬
‫בתוך החומה?‬
‫בלתי אפשרי!‬
‫מפקדת האגף, מה הפקודות?‬
‫אה. ובכן, אני לא בטוחה.‬
‫זה, זה רק צירוף מקרים,‬
‫או ש...?‬
‫הו, לא.‬
‫בטח שזה לא אומר את זה!‬
‫פאסטור ניק?‬
‫תקשיב לי.‬
‫לא משנה מה תעשה,‬
‫אל תיתן לאור השמש לגעת בו!‬
‫ממ.‬
‫*מתקפת הטיטאנים*‬
‫עונה 02 פרק 01‬
‫"טיטאן החיה"‬
‫♪♪ שיר פתיחה, מושר ביפנית...‬
‫♪♪‬
‫בינתיים,‬
‫כיסינו את טיטאן החומה‬
‫ביריעות.‬
‫נראה שזה מחזיק מעמד.‬
‫צעדים נוספים יינקטו‬
‫אחרי השקיעה, מפקדת.‬
‫הבנתי.‬
‫סלח לי, אדוני,‬
‫אבל מה אנחנו אמורים‬
‫להבין מכל זה?‬
‫כלומר, מעולם לא דמיינתי‬
‫שיכולים להיות‬
‫טיטאנים בתוך החומות.‬
‫למה שתדמיין? אף אחד לא דמיין.‬
‫יש רק את אלה שידעו‬
‫ואת אלה מאיתנו‬
‫שנשארו לגמרי באפלה.‬
‫למה הם‬
‫שומרים על שתיקה בנושא?‬
‫זו תגלית מרעידת עולמות,‬
‫למען השם.‬
‫מה הטעם‬
‫להתעלם מזה?‬
‫סטטוס קוו, לא?‬
‫כן, הדרגים הגבוהים‬
‫שומרים את הקלפים קרוב לחזה.‬
‫כל הטבח הזה,‬
‫והם אפילו לא‬
‫טרחו להמציא סיפור כיסוי‬
‫נורמלי.‬
‫טוב.‬
‫אתה רוצה להגיד לי‬
‫מה קורה כאן?‬
‫למה טיטאן?‬
‫מה המטרה?‬
‫מה לעזאזל‬
‫הטעם בלהחזיק אחד‬
‫חבוי בתוך החומה?‬
‫ולמה לבחור‬
‫לשמור את זה בסוד?‬
‫אני צריכה תשובות, ואני צריכה‬
‫אותן ממש עכשיו.‬
‫אין לי זמן‬
‫לשטויות האלה.‬
‫אני אדם עסוק. הקהילה שלי‬
‫הושמדה!‬
‫אני דורש פיצויים!‬
‫את יודעת מי אני?‬
‫תורידי אותי‬
‫מכאן מיד!‬
‫אם זה מה שאתה רוצה.‬
‫נפילה ישר למטה‬
‫תעשה את העבודה?‬
‫מפקדת!‬
‫עצרי!‬
‫תן לי לשאול אותך משהו.‬
‫יש לך מושג כמה סיירים‬
‫קיפחו את חייהם‬
‫בלחימה במפלצות האלה?‬
‫יותר ממה שאתה יכול לספור!‬
‫הם מתו בלחימה‬
‫על החופש שלך!‬
‫אני הייתי איתם!‬
‫הייתי מוכנה‬
‫להקריב את חיי שלי!‬
‫עכשיו, או שתסביר,‬
‫או שתצנח למטה.‬
‫Your choice. I can always‬
‫move on to the next blowhard.‬
‫Matter of fact,‬
‫they'd probably know‬
‫more than you anyway.‬
‫Why am I bothering?‬
‫Let go! Unhand me!‬
‫That's kind of‬
‫what I had in mind.‬
‫Do it!‬
‫Don't try to call my bluff.‬
‫Please, don't!‬
‫You think I'm afraid to die‬
‫in the service of my belief?‬
‫We fulfill our duty‬
‫whatever the cost!‬
‫I don't care!‬
‫The Lord is my shepherd!‬
‫Let his humble servant fall!‬
‫Lord, grant release.‬
‫Lighten up.‬
‫I was just kidding around.‬
‫C'mon,‬
‫Pastor Nick. Spill it.‬
‫Are all the walls‬
‫made of Titans?‬
‫At least tell me that much.‬
‫Section Commander.‬
‫Ugh. How long's it been‬
‫since I felt like this?‬
‫Wow. Must've been‬
‫when I stepped outside‬
‫the walls for the first time.‬
‫Talk about terrifying.‬
‫Hurry! I have‬
‫to tell Commander Erwin!‬
‫Hyah!‬
‫The Titans have‬
‫breached Wall Rose!‬
‫How much‬
‫longer do you think‬
‫- they'll keep us here?‬
‫- Who knows.‬
‫Y'know, my village happens to be‬
‫just a little bit south‬
‫of where we are now.‬
‫Huh. Town where I'm from's‬
‫pretty close by, too.‬
‫Why can't I go see my people?‬
‫Maybe I'll just‬
‫sneak out after dark.‬
‫My people told me not to‬
‫bother coming back home‬
‫till I'm normal, so...‬
‫there's that.‬
‫Hm. Well, folks where I grew‬
‫up always tried to tell me‬
‫I was too puny to be a soldier.‬
‫No question I had‬
‫the brains for it.‬
‫I was top ten‬
‫in my class, actually.‬
‫Somebody's gonna‬
‫be eatin' their words,‬
‫that's a promise.‬
‫Conny, I'll help you‬
‫if you really wanna go.‬
‫Yeah? Why would you?‬
‫Doesn't this feel a bit strange?‬
‫We're on standby‬
‫in our plain clothes.‬
‫They won't let us‬
‫wear our uniforms.‬
‫We can't even train.‬
‫What's even more suspicious:‬
‫our superiors‬
‫are armed to the teeth.‬
‫We're inside the wall,‬
‫not at the front line.‬
‫So who exactly are we fighting?‬
‫I don't know, man.‬
‫Maybe they're‬
‫worried about bears.‬
‫Sure. Bears.‬
‫All you need‬
‫for bears are guns.‬
‫Uh. Guys, I think I'm‬
‫hearing footsteps!‬
‫What?‬
‫Knock if off, Sasha.‬
‫So what, you're trying‬
‫to tell us Titans are here?‬
‫Come on, that would‬
‫only be possible‬
‫if Wall Rose had fallen.‬
‫What is it, Miche?‬
‫Tomas. Ride out of here.‬
‫Take three couriers.‬
‫Notify the districts.‬
‫The odds of there‬
‫being any Titans hiding‬
‫in the hundred and forth‬
‫Cadet Corp are low.‬
‫We've got multiple Titans‬
‫incoming from the south!‬
‫Wall Rose has been compromised!‬
‫Look, I'm not pulling‬
‫your leg! I hear something!‬
‫Is everyone here?‬
‫What it is, Nanaba?‬
‫We've got company.‬
‫Approximately 500 meters‬
‫to the south and closing.‬
‫Titans. Headed this way.‬
‫There's no time to suit up‬
‫with your ODM gear.‬
‫I want everyone on a horse STAT.‬
‫Evacuate every home and‬
‫settlement in the area.‬
‫Get to it.‬
‫The south? But that's...‬
‫Do we know if the wall's‬
‫really been breached?‬
‫Ride! I'm sorry,‬
‫but I'm afraid lunch‬
‫is going to have to wait!‬
‫Miche.‬
‫Nine of them.‬
‫In that swarm up ahead.‬
‫They must've‬
‫broken through Wall Rose.‬
‫Damn it.‬
‫We never even got the chance‬
‫to figure out what in‬
‫god's name these things are.‬
‫Now, it's too late.‬
‫Humanity has lost.‬
‫This is the end.‬
‫Like hell it is.‬
‫We're not done.‬
‫Not yet. A person only‬
‫loses when they give in.‬
‫Remember that.‬
‫As long as we keep‬
‫putting up a fight,‬
‫we haven't been beaten!‬
‫The second the Titans‬
‫reach the woods, we'll split up.‬
‫I want four separate teams.‬
‫Recruits and soldiers‬
‫alike in each unit.‬
‫When I give the signal,‬
‫we'll scatter in different‬
‫directions simultaneously.‬
‫Get the word out to civilians.‬
‫Do not engage the enemy!‬
‫Which one of you is most‬
‫familiar with the area?‬
‫Uh, me!‬
‫Sir, my home town's‬
‫just to the north of here!‬
‫I know this region‬
‫like the back of my hand!‬
‫Conny, too! Go on, tell him!‬
‫What's wrong?‬
‫My village.‬
‫My village is to the south.‬
‫That's where the Titans‬
‫are coming from.‬
‫I can lead you‬
‫to nearby settlements,‬
‫but afterwards...‬
‫let me go home. Please.‬
‫Very well.‬
‫Guide the southern team,‬
‫then go to your village.‬
‫Yes, sir!‬
‫I'll come with you.‬
‫What? No, you're crazy.‬
‫They'll be everywhere.‬
‫You think I care?‬
‫I was gonna help you‬
‫get home anyway, wasn't I?‬
‫What about you? You coming?‬
‫Of course. Wouldn't‬
‫miss it for the world.‬
‫As you have guessed,‬
‫today marks the darkest hour‬
‫in humanity's history!‬
‫Look sharp. If ever‬
‫we needed to give our all,‬
‫that time is now!‬
‫Don't lose heart!‬
‫They've reached the woods!‬
‫The enemy is on top of us!‬
‫Scatter, now!‬
‫Ride for everything‬
‫you're worth!‬
‫No. They're‬
‫coming at us full tilt!‬
‫Huh? Holy shit!‬
‫Gelgar!‬
‫Take charge‬
‫of the southern team!‬
‫Sir?‬
‫Uh, understood.‬
‫Tell me‬
‫he's not using himself as bait!‬
‫I'll go with him!‬
‫I can help!‬
‫Stay where you are!‬
‫We can't spare‬
‫any more soldiers!‬
‫Give him some credit.‬
‫That man's skills are‬
‫second only to Captain Levi.‬
‫He'll make it back alive.‬
‫Count on it!‬
‫Ugh, Eren.‬
‫Another fight? Really?‬
‫Yeah, well, I'm not the one‬
‫who started it this time!‬
‫Those jerks‬
‫were making fun of me!‬
‫Of course. Did Mikasa‬
‫come to your rescue again?‬
‫Thank you, dear.‬
‫Eren, we don't throw‬
‫punches at everyone‬
‫who's mean to us.‬
‫Being an adult means learning‬
‫how to pick your battles.‬
‫You want them to think‬
‫that you're strong?‬
‫Exercise restraint.‬
‫Try protecting Mikasa‬
‫once in a while.‬
‫Oh.‬
‫It fell. Here.‬
‫Get some sleep.‬
‫You've gotta be tired.‬
‫No. I'm okay.‬
‫That thing's‬
‫seen better days.‬
‫I'll grab you a new one if I‬
‫can find any with the supplies.‬
‫ארן! מיקאסה!‬
‫הם פרצו‬
‫את חומת רוז!‬
‫הטיטאנים! הם באים!‬
‫אוף. למה שהממזרים האלה‬
‫לא יתנו לנו רגע של שקט?‬
‫אתה יכול ללכת?‬
‫כאילו שיש ברירה.‬
‫אם יורשה לי לומר, המפקד, זה חכם מאוד‬
‫להשאיר את מיקה אחראי‬
‫על ה-104.‬
‫אם מישהו יכול להתמודד‬
‫עם המצב, זה הוא.‬
‫כן.‬
‫נקווה שכן.‬
‫נשארו רק ארבעה מהם.‬
‫לא. אל תסתכן.‬
‫קניתי לנו‬
‫יותר ממספיק זמן.‬
‫ובכל זאת.‬
‫הטיטאן החריג הזה מדאיג אותי.‬
‫תראה את הממזר הזה.‬
‫בקלות מעל 17‬
‫מטרים. עצום.‬
‫וזו הפעם הראשונה‬
‫שראיתי אחד כזה‬
‫מכוסה ב... מה זה, פרווה?‬
‫הוא סתם משוטט לו.‬
‫למה הוא לא מנסה להסתער עליי?‬
‫בבירור חריג, אבל...‬
‫אה. הנה אתה.‬
‫נראה שלא אצטרך להחזיק מעמד‬
‫עד השקיעה אחרי הכל.‬
‫מה לעזאזל...? הוא הלך על הסוס?‬
‫אוי, נו באמת!‬
‫חכה.‬
‫בטח לא שמעת אותי.‬
‫אמרתי לך לחכות.‬
‫אפשר לשאול איך אתם קוראים‬
‫לנשק המוזר הזה שלכם?‬
‫הדבר שמחובר למותניים שלכם‬
‫שמאפשר לכם לעוף.‬
‫הא. אני די בטוח‬
‫שאנחנו מדברים באותה שפה.‬
‫אולי אתם מפוחדים מדי‬
‫כדי לנסח תשובה?‬
‫שמתי לב שאתם משתמשים גם בחרבות.‬
‫מרתק.‬
‫זה בטח אומר שאתם יודעים‬
‫שאנחנו נמצאים בעורף.‬
‫אה, ובכן.‬
‫נניח שאקח את זה בחזרה איתי.‬
‫עוד לא. אדם מפסיד רק‬
‫כשהוא נכנע.‬
‫כל עוד אנחנו ממשיכים‬
‫להילחם.‬
‫כל עוד‬
‫אנחנו ממשיכים להילחם,‬
‫לא הובסנו!‬
‫הא?‬
‫אה. אתם יכולים לזוז עכשיו.‬
‫לא! לא!‬
‫לא, בבקשה! תפסיק! בבקשה...‬
‫אה, אז אתם יודעים לדבר.‬
‫אה, רעיון חכם‬
‫במיוחד, אני חייב לומר.‬
‫♪ ♪‬
‫♪♪ שיר סיום,‬
‫מילים ביפנית... ♪♪‬
‫♪♪‬